Josh Woodcock // Front-End Software Engineer

832-247-8742 // josh@j0w0.com // github.com/j0w0 // j0w0.com // linkedin.com/in/jrwoodcock

Front-End Software Engineer experienced in building reliable, manageable, and scalable websites and web applications. I develop quality products by utilizing appropriate technologies and applying best practices for data organization and code optimization.

Skills/Technologies: React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SCSS, TypeScript, Vite, Next.js, Node, Express, Google Firebase, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Bootstrap, Tailwind, jQuery, PHP, Git, Jira, creating and consuming RESTful APIs, Wordpress & Headless CMS, WooCommerce. Code and project demos are available on my GitHub.

Experience

Full-Stack Developer

Hahn Agency | May 2022-Present | Austin, Texas

- Built a Learning Management System consisting of webinar video content, quizzes, and levels for achievement badges.
- Develop, implement, and maintain new features for client websites, apps, and content management systems.
- Tech stack includes React, JavaScript, HTML, SCSS/CSS, PHP, MySQL, Wordpress.

Front-End Software Engineer

Music Audience Exchange (MAX) | January 2021-May 2022 | Austin, Texas

- Developed front end of brand and artist web apps for streaming concerts, including real-time chat and donations.
- Simplified development process for quicker turnaround by creating standardized templates for content and layout.
- Tech stack used includes React, Styled Components, Google Firebase, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

Front-End/UX Developer

Remedy Urgent Care | January 2019-July 2020 | Austin, Texas

- Streamlined urgent care web app that helped win two stages of funding for the start-up. By leveraging open-source web technologies, e-commerce, and custom form flows, the app was easily managed, scaled, and monitored.
- Developed admin utilities to help service coordinators better assist patients during the scheduling process.
- Tech stack used includes PHP, MySQL, Wordpress, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Twilio, WooCommerce.

Web Developer

Ford Audio-Video | January 2017-January 2019 | Austin, Texas

- Architected/developed custom Wordpress theme and plugins allowing for easier management and sharing of content.
- Developed and maintained full-stack web apps in PHP and MySQL for marketing events that included customer and exhibitor registration, check in and attendance, lead tracking, and online payments via Stripe.
- Tech stack used includes PHP, MySQL, Wordpress, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Twilio, Stripe.

Digital Media Marketing Coordinator

Ford Audio-Video | July 2014-January 2017 | Austin, Texas

 Maintained earlier versions of the company's website, event landing pages, and staff Intranet. Designed and developed responsive email template for marketing promotions. Promoted to Engineering as Web Developer.

Education

Texas State University